<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Arete Blog</title>
    <link>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Arete Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 22:23:18 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Negatively</title>
      <link>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/first/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 22:23:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/first/</guid>
      <description>Feeling ready to do something does not mean feeling certain that you&amp;rsquo;ll succeed, though of course that&amp;rsquo;s what you are hoping to do. Truly being ready means understanding what could go wrong – and having a plan to deal with it.
Chris Hadfield, An Astronaut&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Life on Earth
Eliud Kipchoge is considered the greatest marathon runner of all time. As with the most iconic athletes, the principles and values they embody are far more relevant than their achievements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Favorite ideas</title>
      <link>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/quotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/quotes/</guid>
      <description>Edith Eger &amp;ldquo;Our painful experiences aren&amp;rsquo;t a liability—they&amp;rsquo;re a gift. They give us perspective and meaning, an opportunity to find our unique purpose and our strength.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s the first time I see that we have a choice: to pay attention to what we&amp;rsquo;ve lost or to pay attention to what we still have.&amp;rdquo; &amp;mdash; Edith Eger, The Choice: Embrace the Possible
Suffering is universal. But victimhood is optional. There is a difference between victimization and victimhood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Me</title>
      <link>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/about/</guid>
      <description>This is Andres.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posts Archive</title>
      <link>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/archive/</guid>
      <description>2023 04 Feb &amp;ndash; Thinking Negatively</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading List</title>
      <link>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/reading_list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/reading_list/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of the books I&amp;rsquo;ve ever read and the ones I&amp;rsquo;d like to read.
Next The 48 Laws of Power Build: An Unorthodox Guide to Making Things Worth Making Never Finished How to Think Like A Rocket Scientist The Hard Things About the Hard Things The Courage to be Disliked The Ego is the Enemy Stillness is the Key The Lean Startup Books read Atomic Habits by James Clear Be Water, My Friend Man&amp;rsquo;s Search for Meaning The War of Art The Art of War The Midnigth Library Meditations When Things Fall Apart How to meditate How to Think Like a Roman Emperor The Obstacle is the Way The Art of a Good Life The Proof is in the Plants Sapiens 21 lessons for the XXI century Infinite Powers Factfulness Siddhartha Farenheit 451 1984 Code Breaker Steve Jobs El día que se perdió la cordura The Gift Shackleton Bajo el Aro El libro Negro del Emprendedor Innovadores Steve Wozniak An Austronauts Guide to Life on Earth The future of Humanity Shoe The Psychology of Money Elon Musk El legado de Mandela Zero to One The Myth of Artificial Intelligence </description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
