<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Andres Blog</title>
    <link>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Andres Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 16:23:18 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Edith Eger (IV): And then what?</title>
      <link>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/edith_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 16:23:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/edith_4/</guid>
      <description>Edith and her sister Magda achieved what seemed impossible: to get out of Auschwitz alive. They survived the most lethal Nazi concentration and extermination camp, where nearly one million people died. But they were not free. Not yet. When Nazi Germany was on the verge of defeat, the SS organized “death marches”, forced evacuations of concentration camps over long distances under guard and extremely harsh conditions.
Edith and Magda were moved to other concentration camps like Mauthausen, where prisoners were made to hack and carry granite to construct Hitler&amp;rsquo;s desired new capital for Germany.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edith Eger (III): Gratitude</title>
      <link>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/edith_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 18:23:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/edith_3/</guid>
      <description>Right after arriving at Auschwitz, Edith and her mother and sister were waiting in the selection line. They didn&amp;rsquo;t know it, but this would be their last moment together. While Edith and her sister Magda were sent to the left, their mother was sent to the right.
When Edith, just sixteen, entered the camp and asked where her mother was, one of the women dressed in striped dresses pointed to the smoke rising up from one of the chimneys in the distance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edith Eger (II): The power within you</title>
      <link>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/edith_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 17:23:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/edith_2/</guid>
      <description>When I started university, I met a girl. She was funny, pretty, and kind, and I completely fell in love with her. It was an amazing feeling. The problem was that I was very shy and introverted, and sometimes connecting with others wasn&amp;rsquo;t easy. Because I didn&amp;rsquo;t have confidence in myself, and I was the only one who seemed to have this issue, I assumed that something was wrong with me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edith Eger (I): You have a choice</title>
      <link>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/edith_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 13:23:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/edith_1/</guid>
      <description>Edith Eger is a hero of mine. She was born in 1927 and grew up in Nazi-occupied Europe. When she was sixteen, Edith and her family were sent to Auschwitz. She and her sister Magda survived, but their parents and nearly everyone she loved did not. When the Nazi concentration camps were liberated, she was discovered under a pile of dead bodies. Edith was severely malnourished, and had a broken back, pneumonia, and typhoid fever, among others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>By endurance we conquer</title>
      <link>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/shackleton/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 21:23:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/shackleton/</guid>
      <description>In 1914, Ernest Shackleton chose one of the most audacious goals at that time: make the first land crossing of the Antarctic continent. It was inconceivable that a group of people could do that. And they failed, but are not remembered as a failure—quite the opposite.
Just a couple of months after their departure, Shackleton&amp;rsquo;s trip, the Endurance, became trapped in ice and eventually sank. They spent several months in the harsh Antarctic, isolated from human civilization, trying to survive under extreme conditions with temperatures reaching minus 40º and winds reaching up to 200 km/h.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I take cold showers</title>
      <link>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/cold_showers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 22:23:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/cold_showers/</guid>
      <description>Do difficult things every day. Step out of your comfort zone daily because that will callous your mind. Sounds good, so I researched cold showers and discovered they have been shown to have several benefits, including reduced inflammation, reduced stress levels, boosted energy, increased immunity, and enhanced focus, among others. And because I considered them as self-imposed torture, I decided to take cold showers every morning. Then, everything went differently than planned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to TFX pipelines</title>
      <link>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/tfx_tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 18:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/tfx_tutorial/</guid>
      <description>NOTE : This tutorial is a personal wrap-up of the TFX Pipeline Tutorial using the Penguin Dataset. The code used is identical, but I have added an introduction to TFX and several explanations for every section. The goal of this post to document my learning notes about TFX.
What is TFX, and why is needed?
Machine Learning is more than getting data, training models, and making predictions. A wide range of constraints and requirements need to be addressed for ML to add value in the real world:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrieval stage recommender systems with TensorFlow</title>
      <link>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/retrieval_tf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 22:23:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/retrieval_tf/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to recommender systems Some of the most exciting features that big companies like Amazon, Netflix, and Spotify offer rely on recommender systems. Much useful information can be collected whenever users navigate the Amazon website, listen to a playlist on Spotify, or scroll through the Netflix catalog. This data includes user behavior, item attributes, or interactions between users and is what machine learning recommender systems use to make personalized recommendations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You who are passing by</title>
      <link>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/charlotte_poem/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 22:23:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/charlotte_poem/</guid>
      <description>You who are passing by
I beg you
Do something
Learn a dance step
Something to justify your existence
Something that gives you the right
To be dressed in your skin in your body
Learn to walk and to laugh
Because it would be too senseless
After all
For many to have died
While you live
Doing nothing with your life
Auschwitz survivor Charlotte</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Negatively</title>
      <link>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/think_negatively/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 22:23:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/think_negatively/</guid>
      <description>Feeling ready to do something does not mean feeling certain that you&amp;rsquo;ll succeed, though of course that&amp;rsquo;s what you are hoping to do. Truly being ready means understanding what could go wrong – and having a plan to deal with it.
Chris Hadfield, An Astronaut&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Life on Earth
Eliud Kipchoge is considered the greatest marathon runner of all time. As with the most iconic athletes, the principles and values they embody are far more relevant than their achievements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Favorite ideas</title>
      <link>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/quotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/quotes/</guid>
      <description>Edith Eger &amp;ldquo;Our painful experiences aren&amp;rsquo;t a liability—they&amp;rsquo;re a gift. They give us perspective and meaning, an opportunity to find our unique purpose and our strength.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s the first time I see that we have a choice: to pay attention to what we&amp;rsquo;ve lost or to pay attention to what we still have.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Survivors don&amp;rsquo;t have time to ask, &amp;lsquo;Why me?&amp;rsquo; For survivors, the only relevant question is, &amp;lsquo;What now?&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/ms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/ms/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Me</title>
      <link>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/about/</guid>
      <description>This is Andres.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posts Archive</title>
      <link>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/archive/</guid>
      <description>2023 27 May &amp;ndash; Edith Eger (IV): And then what?
16 Apr &amp;ndash; Edith Eger (III): Gratitude
16 Apr &amp;ndash; Edith Eger (II): The power within you
16 Apr &amp;ndash; Edith Eger (I): You have a choice
14 Feb &amp;ndash; By endurance we conquer
13 Feb &amp;ndash; Why I take cold showers
12 Feb &amp;ndash; Introduction to TFX pipelines
11 Feb &amp;ndash; Retrieval stage recommender systems with TensorFlow
07 Feb &amp;ndash; You who are passing by</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading</title>
      <link>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/reading_list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/reading_list/</guid>
      <description>Next Build: An Unorthodox Guide to Making Things Worth Making by Tony Fadell Outlive: The science and art of longevity by Dr Peter Attia The beginning of infinity by David Deutsch Books read Meditations by Marcus Aurelius When Things Fall Apart by Pema Chödron How to meditate by Pema Chödron Can&amp;rsquo;t Hurt Me by David Goggins The Gift: 12 lessons to save your life by Edith Eger The Choice: A true story of hope by Edith Eger Atomic Habits by James Clear Be Water, My Friend by Shannon Lee Man&amp;rsquo;s Search for Meaning by Viktor Frankl The War of Art by Steven Pressfield The Midnigth Library by Matt Haig How to Think Like a Roman Emperor by Donald Robertson The Obstacle is the Way by Ryan Holiday The Art of a Good Life by William B.</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
