<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>ML on Andres Blog</title>
    <link>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/tags/ml/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ML on Andres Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 18:30:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/tags/ml/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to TFX pipelines</title>
      <link>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/tfx_tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 18:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/tfx_tutorial/</guid>
      <description>NOTE : This tutorial is a personal wrap-up of the TFX Pipeline Tutorial using the Penguin Dataset. The code used is identical, but I have added an introduction to TFX and several explanations for every section. The goal of this post to document my learning notes about TFX.
What is TFX, and why is needed?
Machine Learning is more than getting data, training models, and making predictions. A wide range of constraints and requirements need to be addressed for ML to add value in the real world:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrieval stage recommender systems with TensorFlow</title>
      <link>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/retrieval_tf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 22:23:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/retrieval_tf/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to recommender systems Some of the most exciting features that big companies like Amazon, Netflix, and Spotify offer rely on recommender systems. Much useful information can be collected whenever users navigate the Amazon website, listen to a playlist on Spotify, or scroll through the Netflix catalog. This data includes user behavior, item attributes, or interactions between users and is what machine learning recommender systems use to make personalized recommendations.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
