<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Andres Blog</title>
    <link>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Andres Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 09:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Power of Urgency</title>
      <link>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/a-sense-of-urgency/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/a-sense-of-urgency/</guid>
      <description>The Power of Urgency We&amp;rsquo;ve all been there. Standing at the edge of our comfort zone, heart pounding, your dreams so close. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s that book you&amp;rsquo;ve always talked about writing, or the marathon you&amp;rsquo;ve been putting off, or that ticket to a far-off place with a name you can barely pronounce.
You can see it, feel it, almost taste it. But when it&amp;rsquo;s time to turn that vision into reality, something strange happens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aim high</title>
      <link>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/aim-high/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/aim-high/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Ideas are like fish. If you want to catch small fish, you can stay in the shallow water. But if you want to catch the big fish, you have to go deeper. In the deep, the fish are more powerful and pure. They are giant and abstract. And they are very beautiful. ~David Lynch
The goals we set for ourselves are like fish. Do we choose a small fish or a big one?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Control your emotions</title>
      <link>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/control-your-emotions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 07:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/control-your-emotions/</guid>
      <description>A lot of people find writing difficult. I think so too. When I first started writing, there wasn&amp;rsquo;t a day that went by that I didn&amp;rsquo;t end up frustrated. When I tried to articulate an idea, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find the words. Often I had no idea what I was writing about. It still happens.
When I was really frustrated and wanted to give up, I thought the main problem was that writing was complicated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ask good questions</title>
      <link>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 06:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/questions/</guid>
      <description>In the science fiction saga The Hitchhiker&amp;rsquo;s Guide to the Galaxy, a group of space explorers search for the answer to the meaning of life by creating a supercomputer. After seven million years of work, the supercomputer comes up with the answer: 42.
To everyone&amp;rsquo;s astonishment, the computer replies: &amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s definitely the answer. I think the problem, to be honest, is that you didn&amp;rsquo;t really know what the question was&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take a step back</title>
      <link>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/take-a-step-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 05:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/take-a-step-back/</guid>
      <description>At the age of thirteen, Bruce Lee discovered his true passion: martial arts. He practiced every day, all the time. He was so talented, skilled, hard-working and driven. No one doubted he would be unstoppable. He devoted himself body and soul to the discipline. But there was a problem.
From time to time, Yip Man, his teacher, tried to teach him key ideas: &amp;ldquo;Never impose yourself on nature. It flows&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;never oppose any problem head on, but counter it by balancing with it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The power of incentives</title>
      <link>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/the-power-of-incentives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 04:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/the-power-of-incentives/</guid>
      <description>In the 19th century, the British government faced a critical dilemma when it came to transporting prisoners to Australia. The prisoner survival rate was a worrying 40 per cent. In an effort to improve it, various government organizations and humanitarian groups proposed improvements. But after several attempts, the survival rate remained at 40 per cent.
The situation did not improve until Edwin Chadwick, a visionary economist, decided to change the focus of the problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aim to be a zero</title>
      <link>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/aim-to-be-a-zero/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 03:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/aim-to-be-a-zero/</guid>
      <description>Nelson Mandela spent his life fighting to overthrow apartheid and bring democracy to South Africa, where all South Africans, regardless of their social status or color, would be allowed to vote.
He was imprisoned for 27 years. He endured hard labor, severe isolation and very basic living conditions. He had to overcome internal conflicts within his political movement, whose members had doubts about the best course of action for the overthrow of apartheid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who are you becoming</title>
      <link>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/who-are-you-becoming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 02:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/who-are-you-becoming/</guid>
      <description>Hundreds of millions of people were watching television. It has been an intense decade of relentless work, without rest. Expectation was at an all-time high. Too much was at stake. It was 20 July 1969, and two American astronauts were about to become the first humans to set foot on the moon.
Eight years earlier, President Kennedy had inspired an entire nation by announcing his goal of putting a man on the moon before the end of the decade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Choice of Hercules</title>
      <link>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/the-choice-of-hercules/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 02:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/the-choice-of-hercules/</guid>
      <description>This article is about the story of The Choice of Hercules&amp;rsquo;, which is a metaphor for the ability we all have to make choices and the consequences of those choices. The version of The Choice of Hercules presented here is an excerpt from Donald Robertson&amp;rsquo;s book How to Think Like a Roman Emperor.
One day, as a young man, Hercules was walking along an unfamiliar path when he came upon a fork in the road, where he sat down and began contemplating his future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create your own future</title>
      <link>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/create_future/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 16:23:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/create_future/</guid>
      <description>SPOILER ALERT: This blogpost is based on the book Lessons In Chemistry and contains spoilers.
Elizabeth Zott hated being in class, sitting at a desk listening to monotonous teachers talking about boring subjects. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t that she didn&amp;rsquo;t enjoy learning. She loved it. But all the learning there was based on memorisation, and Elizabeth liked creativity. Elizabeth also disliked her classmates who did not share her hobbies. And all this made her suffer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I wish you bad luck by John Roberts</title>
      <link>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/i_wish-you_bad_luck/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 22:23:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/i_wish-you_bad_luck/</guid>
      <description>This is a excerpt from the graduation speech that John Roberts, Chief Justice of the Supreme Court of the United States, delivered at his son&amp;rsquo;s high school in Cardigan on 3 June 2017:
From time to time in the years to come, I hope you will be treated unfairly, so that you will come to know the value of justice.
I hope that you will suffer betrayal because that will teach you the importance of loyalty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edith Eger (IV): And now what?</title>
      <link>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/edith_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 16:23:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/edith_4/</guid>
      <description>Edith and her sister Magda achieved what seemed impossible: to get out of Auschwitz alive. They survived the most lethal Nazi concentration and extermination camp, where nearly one million people died. But they were not free. Not yet. When Nazi Germany was on the verge of defeat, the SS organized “death marches”, forced evacuations of concentration camps over long distances under guard and extremely harsh conditions.
Edith and Magda were moved to other concentration camps like Mauthausen, where prisoners were made to hack and carry granite to construct Hitler&amp;rsquo;s desired new capital for Germany.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edith Eger (III): Gratitude</title>
      <link>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/edith_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 18:23:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/edith_3/</guid>
      <description>Right after arriving at Auschwitz, Edith and her mother and sister were waiting in the selection line. They didn&amp;rsquo;t know it, but this would be their last moment together. While Edith and her sister Magda were sent to the left, their mother was sent to the right.
When Edith, just sixteen, entered the camp and asked where her mother was, one of the women dressed in striped dresses pointed to the smoke rising up from one of the chimneys in the distance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edith Eger (II): The power within you</title>
      <link>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/edith_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 17:23:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/edith_2/</guid>
      <description>When I started university, I met a girl. She was funny, pretty, and kind, and I completely fell in love with her. It was an amazing feeling. The problem was that I was very shy and introverted, and sometimes connecting with others wasn&amp;rsquo;t easy. Because I didn&amp;rsquo;t have confidence in myself, and I was the only one who seemed to have this issue, I assumed that something was wrong with me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edith Eger (I): You have a choice</title>
      <link>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/edith_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 13:23:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/edith_1/</guid>
      <description>Edith Eger is a hero of mine. She was born in 1927 and grew up in Nazi-occupied Europe. When she was sixteen, Edith and her family were sent to Auschwitz. She and her sister Magda survived, but their parents and nearly everyone she loved did not. When the Nazi concentration camps were liberated, she was discovered under a pile of dead bodies. Edith was severely malnourished, and had a broken back, pneumonia, and typhoid fever, among others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>By endurance we conquer</title>
      <link>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/shackleton/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 21:23:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/shackleton/</guid>
      <description>In 1914, Ernest Shackleton chose one of the most audacious goals at that time: make the first land crossing of the Antarctic continent. It was inconceivable that a group of people could do that. And they failed, but are not remembered as a failure—quite the opposite.
Just a couple of months after their departure, Shackleton&amp;rsquo;s trip, the Endurance, became trapped in ice and eventually sank. They spent several months in the harsh Antarctic, isolated from human civilization, trying to survive under extreme conditions with temperatures reaching minus 40º and winds reaching up to 200 km/h.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I take cold showers</title>
      <link>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/cold_showers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 22:23:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/cold_showers/</guid>
      <description>Do difficult things every day. Step out of your comfort zone daily because that will callous your mind. Sounds good, so I researched cold showers and discovered they have been shown to have several benefits, including reduced inflammation, reduced stress levels, boosted energy, increased immunity, and enhanced focus, among others. And because I considered them as self-imposed torture, I decided to take cold showers every morning. Then, everything went differently than planned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You who are passing by</title>
      <link>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/charlotte_poem/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 22:23:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/charlotte_poem/</guid>
      <description>You who are passing by
I beg you
Do something
Learn a dance step
Something to justify your existence
Something that gives you the right
To be dressed in your skin in your body
Learn to walk and to laugh
Because it would be too senseless
After all
For many to have died
While you live
Doing nothing with your life
Auschwitz survivor Charlotte</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Negatively</title>
      <link>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/think_negatively/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 22:23:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andresruizc.github.io/andresr/posts/think_negatively/</guid>
      <description>Feeling ready to do something does not mean feeling certain that you&amp;rsquo;ll succeed, though of course that&amp;rsquo;s what you are hoping to do. Truly being ready means understanding what could go wrong – and having a plan to deal with it.
Chris Hadfield, An Astronaut&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Life on Earth
Eliud Kipchoge is considered the greatest marathon runner of all time. As with the most iconic athletes, the principles and values they embody are far more relevant than their achievements.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
